Sophie Berger

BSc in Computer Science and Masters of Management student at UBC Android, iOS, Web and AR experience

Microsoft Imagine cup Regional Finalist, Startup Equity Owner

+1 (236) 862-3848 berger.m.sophie@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sophiemb github.com/SophieMBerger sophiemberger.github.io/

"Strength Insight Report" (from Gallup / CliftonStrengths): Achiever, Strategic, Learner, Futuristic, Focus

Skills

Proficient: Python, Java, Swift, SwiftUI, Firebase,

ARKit

Familiar: C, C++, Kotlin, JavaScript, React,

Tensorflow, HTML, CSS

Experience

HCI Undergraduate Researcher 03/ 2020 – 08/ 2020 USRA/SURE awards through UBC

- Grounded-theory methodology
- Support systems for elderly during COVID-19
- Supervised by Prof. Dongwook Yoon

Equity-owner of "Mindset" startup 10/2019 – Present iOS Expert/equity-owner

(https://mindsetapp.co.uk/)

- <u>Front-end development</u> on dementia screening iOS app using **Swift**
- Analyzed iOS UI/UX compatibility
- <u>Implemented</u> number recognition OCR dementia test, using **Swift/SwiftUI**

Tailored Apps

05/2019 – 07/2019

iOS Software Developer Intern

- <u>Built</u> proof-of-concept for €30,000 project deal
- Helped CTO estimate project feasibility/pricing
- <u>Implemented</u> **Firebase** authentication/Cloud Functions
- Added AR and object recognition using ARKit

Competitions

Microsoft Imagine Cup Regional Finalist

05/2019

Americas regional final

(bit.ly/imaginenekotap)

- In top 12 teams out 30,000+ participants in the Americas
- Presented at the Microsoft Build conference
- Same as "nekoTap" project below

1st place at nwHacks with "nekoTap"

01/2019

Western Canada's largest Hackathon (1000+ participants)

(devpost.com/software/nekotap)

- Android app for improved drug adherence using NFC technology to receive tailored drug information
- <u>Designed</u> animations using Lottie library, <u>implemented</u> Android front-end using **Java** to increase accessibility within the app

Education/Courses

BSc in Computer Science 09/ 2018 – 12/ 2022 + Master of Management: 09/ 2018 – 12/ 2023

- Average = 83.5%, Dean's honor list
- Relevant courses: Models of computation,
 Software construction, Introduction to Computer
 Systems, Basic Algorithms and Data Structures

"Java Foundations Certified Junior 03/ 2017

Associate" - Oracle University

"Machine Learning" – Stanford (Coursera) 06/2020

Selected projects

"Central: Parking Search"

05/2020

Published iOS app in Apple App Store (https://apple.co/2WixQEL)

- Featured 1500+ times in "Navigation" category
- Ranked 87th best "Navigation" app in Austria
- Finds best parking location given destinations
- Built with Swift/SwiftUI, MapKit & CoreLocation

Soil TopARgraphy

10/ 2018 – 09/2019

Android & Unity Developer for UBC Launchpad (eml.ubc.ca/projects/soil-topargraphy/)

- Presented at UBC "MURC" Conference
- AR app for Dr. Maja Krzic's soil science class at UBC (250+ students)
- Created Android front-end using Kotlin and Java
- <u>Utilized</u> Google Maps Android SDK for location

Google NIMA in TensorFlow Lite

07/2019

Proof of concept for TailoredApps (bit.ly/TFLiteGoogleNIMA)

- <u>Converted</u> existing "<u>Neural Image Assessment</u>" models to <u>TensorFlow Lite</u> models using <u>Python</u>
- <u>Developed</u> iOS project, using **Swift**, to <u>rank</u> <u>images</u> / determine the "best" overall image

Community Involvement

nwPlus Engagement Coordinator 04/2020- Present

- Organizing three hackathons, including Western Canada's largest hackathon ("nwHacks")
- Collaborating with organizers, businesses, hackers

Microsoft Student Partner (MSP) 09/2019 - Present

<u>Represent</u> Microsoft and <u>educate</u> about technology